today we will continue to tackle the
beast that is the inside of the base i
need to check that my two villagers are
still okay
we're okay and what we're gonna do is
fill out
both sides of the mansion
this has been an absolute nightmare
because mobs continuously spawn which
has caused me to frustratingly place as
many torches as possible but i have
worked out what i'm going to do
just for this little space here but
we're gonna come back to that as i'm not
mentally prepared for it and i've got
something a little more important to
take care of right now and that is
retaliation so i've been obviously
trading with these villagers non-stop
it's kind of how my main source of
income is these villages and every now
and again i keep hearing
a ding bell from impulse and i can't
find the stupid thing anywhere
so to retaliate
we're gonna go and create our own noise
machine in impulse's base and it's gonna
be
10 million times worse
it's not even meant to be annoying to
find it's just gonna be
pure annoying wait i'm not even in the
portal
we're gonna need some of these
impulse is always online it seems
especially when i'm on like i can't see
anything so i'm kind of forced to work
on my secret base while he's here so
here it is impulse's base
and we better just check that he's uh
he's not home right now because he could
be now obviously i
i can't let you guys know
where this secret base is okay i can
confirm that he is not here so i have an
issue right let's just pretend that my
secret base is in here for a second now
i've been trying to figure out how i can
gain access to this room secretly
without a button or a pressure plate or
anything so i thought maybe chorus fruit
would work
the problem is if i use chorus fruit i
always except this time i'm on the
inside most of the time when i eat a
fruit i end up on the floor
at the diamonds he didn't take the
diamonds so
there's free game right there's one one
way to distract me wow
that was an
eight vayne he shall never know so yeah
the issue is that chorus fruit is
diamonds i'm never gonna get to the end
of this sentence if i keep getting
diamonds every time i try and say this
sentence then i'm happy is impulse so
rich that he just doesn't care no more
shiny distractions okay so basically
chorus fruit is a no-go
even i don't even know how you get out
of here look i try and chorus fruit out
and i always end up that back at the
bottom
so chorus fruit i have decided is not a
good way to enter the base in fact you
could say it gets pretty annoying there
we go we're in so retaliation time
the most annoying and the cheapest and
simplest way to make a noise machine is
a single bell and two observers so you
place one here and you place one here
we're about to add eight of these oh
what happens if you do
what if you double it up
oh my goodness hold on we're about we're
about to make impulses base the worst
this is horrible wait you could just put
two on each side i should have got more
bells we need more cowbell oh no he's
not even here and i want to make it stop
now do i risk the chorus fruit and try
and get out nope
we're down the bottom again right so
let's let's use the chorus fruit and
actually go to the secret base you know
chorus fruit wasn't working for me so i
just went in the old-fashioned way and
um
it's the worst sunday morning in this
secret base too bad sound proofing
doesn't work in minecraft
we're gonna have to
need a we need a button or something to
turn this off i'm losing my mind in here
you know what
why don't i think of this
oh
bliss
bliss okay so while we're here why don't
we see um how many diamonds we got from
impulses uh excavating
i mean i this is my base too so i see
this as fair game 29 diamonds not bad
does this still work you know what this
is how we do it this is how we pass the
time in here they will hear the bells
we will hear the jukebox
oh we need our parrots in here it turns
out there's not a lot to do in your
secret base
oh no oh no no no no oh my i was just
i was afk i was afk and i've been i've
been spotted hold on
they didn't they did they didn't turn
this off um well we know that there's an
easy way out of this
later nerds
no i think that it's over isn't it
it's over oh my god why wasn't i paying
attention i was
just afk
why did i do that okay okay dang it i
just i left my computer for two seconds
it's cause the bells weren't going i
forgot that i was even here i just heard
some block noises like oh
the delivery boys here uh i guess that
was really dumb of me
all right let's let's get
let's get them in a call shall we i
that was i've lost it okay well i better
explain what i've done
all right all right hear me out hit me
out okay
i don't know if i can hear anything
green no yeah okay listen um
it was driving me mad right the bells
were driving me mad and i was thinking
about my next steps and so i turned off
the music of minecraft and i kind of
forgot that you guys were there and i
was just afk and then i just hear a
couple of blocks being picked up i
started panic and i think i've been
i've been rumbled
you've been wrong
yeah
i actually brought b-dubs to help me
find i knew you had a secret baby
because nobody can keep their mouth shut
in the comments but
you had a secret base in here i brought
b dubs to help me find it but you let us
right yeah that was i can't believe how
stupid i am here let me show you what i
did because like i don't think you
noticed how many how much lengths i went
to to hide this thing so well no i've
been looking all over for because i you
they said that you had another base in
here
my secret base is right here
and this
i i extended i extended this corner
over here and you didn't notice so to be
fair i like i added it and i can't
notice and just to make sure that you
wouldn't notice there was anything up i
added an empty room on the other side so
the symmetry was there so there's an
empty room here
a bit of a backup
just so you wouldn't notice that
something was up with your highly
symmetrical base
no no i didn't notice at all i noticed
this kind of stuff where you had like
pokey outfits and parrots hidden and
stuff because he was making noise but
i added i didn't i added the bells of
retaliation but this did not this did
not go to plan at all
dang it oh no so now i just got to find
your base oh
yeah
yeah i found it you found it
i found it what were you doing in my
base
uh
yeah impulse would you like to explain
it's not in your base
exactly i actually
i replicated a little bit of your base
inside of me like this
[Music]
okay
that uh
this is why we made him uh head of
diversionary tactics in the mycelium
he's a big brain he's got a big brain
he's got a big so that's it that's it
game over now we've all been rumbled
unless
unless you want to you want to keep
going
well it has been fun there's plenty of
people on the server that haven't had a
secret base in their base and i'm i'm
not done i mean i just made a really
foolish error and i got rumbled um but
there are plenty of people with big
bases
that
i feel like i feel like we could target
are you in on you want to get in on this
b-dubs i mean it was just me
i mean i yeah i just have only seen this
from the outside i definitely i haven't
even made a secret base yet i want in
okay okay okay okay we need we need to
choose our target very um carefully
yes because
i hate to say it like i don't know where
i would have gone in your base from here
impulse like look down
how many options do you see
down there
i think i would have noticed anything
you put down there for sure despite your
your base being the way it is like
there's actually not a lot of places to
hide a base
uh so
i mean how do you feel about corrales's
base he has the most
most base i guess you'd call it and plus
so many places to hide
oh my gosh yes
yes i think that's a fantastic idea i
was actually just over there so i've got
i got a little bit of a scout of the
place oh oh oh there he is now i have
motive okay so oh
it's perfect
so
i'm thinking we all need to make an
individual
secret base and see how long we can how
long we can keep it a secret from
corrales
okay i mean this is like a competition i
guess so because the hermits like kind
of know that we've been doing a whole
little secret base thing but i don't i
don't think anyone would ever expect
like three people to make a secret base
in your base do you know what i mean
like no that would be insane it is just
so it's just nuts okay should we go and
scout it out maybe he's there at the
moment but let's we can just we can walk
around it's not suspicious
yeah yeah just enjoying the city oh this
is perfect look at it look at the
complexity of this that i can see 10
secret bases right there he's not in his
office can we each have our own skyrise
where's beethoven
don't go to the office
that's all i gotta say are we calling
dibs right now no no no no no
well
i don't want to know where your secret
base is i don't know where your secret
base is
we're kind of making mistake number one
right here because if we broadcast this
to the world uh
definitely we're not gonna i mean
guys we're just pranking he's right
there
let's let's let's go slightly further
away let's go over to jevin's base
because otherwise chris is gonna
i just get suspicious
fly by i hope he didn't see us oh boy
okay right so huddle up i have a
solution to this problem right so
obviously we can't upload anything
without our audience telling the world
it's
yeah it doesn't matter how much you ask
hey guys don't don't tell anyone because
it doesn't work they don't listen
so i have a solution and it's pretty
elegant right so what we're going to do
is we're going to tell everyone in the
hermit uh hermitcraft team don't watch
each other's videos don't watch our
videos we're up to some shenanigans
right okay
step one they're in the they're in the
dark but we can't stop the audience
because they're watching our video
they're watching us right now this very
conversation they're listening to and
they're also they're also wondering how
do i get around this plan that green's
about to explain well they can't because
what i'm gonna do is ask all the other
bits of the audience the ones that can
keep a secret hey
why don't you leave a comment on
not people's not the bass not corrales
yes yes if you can't beat them join them
spread it like just tell tango that
there's there's secret bases in his base
we can't let corrales know and the only
way is that the the information is so
jumbled in amongst all of the
the secrecy that he can't he doesn't
know what the truth is
just to be clear do not go and
infinitely spam the hermit's comment
section if there's already a few
comments just leave a thumbs up on your
favorite ones and leave it at that they
only need a few bits of diversionary
tactics let's be respectful everyone's
gonna be paranoid i love it all right
well
secret base time happy birthday
yeah
wait he's right there no no no no okay
no no no no
he's not online good call well speaking
of corrales
that's a bit scary
he has asked me yet again for another
personal delivery this time i don't have
to do a pesky bird delivery but he asked
me for three
full shulker boxes of quartz block and
some bricks which we're now going to
take to the barge so that he can pick up
man this this man has a need for blocks
that i cannot keep up with but while
we're here let's go and feed the stray
cat shall we gotta keep this thing nice
and fed there we go eat well
sweet stone prince
i don't know how many golden apples it
needs cool so we fed the cat we need to
do a quick stop at the barge
to deliver corrales goods okay today's
price is 75 diamonds that's a really
good deal if you know how much of a pain
it is to get your hand on blocks of
quartz like this it's a serious amount
and of course there's smooth as well
which means smelting corrales
you're the best customer that the barge
has to be honest and it seems like the
timer is steadily going down on whatever
this is the uh hcbbs the hermitcraft big
brain
society i
i don't know now we go back to the base
oh actually before we go back to the
base i need to show you
something i don't know if anyone's
talking about it this is the biggest
scandal
look
people been giving me some slack about
the back of my mansion look at the back
of the diamond throne there is no back
to the diamond throne
there's been some serious mismanagement
of funds and
there's still a there's still a lull up
there
oh man i think i think someone missed a
law
okay now we're going back to the base
admittedly most of the diamonds are on
the tree so i spent quite a substantial
amount of time
gathering up my next set of blocks that
i need
including mostly wherever they've gone
warped stem which is an absolute pain to
collect but this is um kind of my accent
color to the inside now what we're going
to do is we're going to try and enclose
this main area and detail
some of these bits because it's looking
quite plain and i also want to try and
light it up a little bit better so i can
get rid of some of these torches
so that's the plan and of course we're
gonna hop into a time lapse to do it so
that you don't have to watch
six to ten hours of me
placing blocks okay right you ready
let's go
[Music]
it may not look like a lot but
essentially i've built an entire shell
with all of these walls going in and all
the detailing i've actually run out of
blocks annoyingly i've run out of blocks
for the detailing and for those of you
that complain about my torch spam this
guy
is why
i cannot stop all of the mobs spawning
fast enough obviously i'm halfway
through building this thing and i've got
to stop the mobs attacking me this isn't
creative mode this is so this is pure
survival and if you have even one dark
spot you've got creepers you've got
damage hence i would rather have torch
spam than a million holes in my base
either way
oh goodness you hear that
it doesn't matter how many torches you
spam
you end up with
this
get out of here
more torches
oh for goodness you can't you can't win
well anyway i'm pretty happy with how
the interior has come along we now have
some walls and we basically have the
shell
to this inner room the great hall the
great green hall of mansion i i'm really
enjoying this i think this looks
brilliant i'm having some issues with
lighting it all up as you can probably
tell i'm kind of fond of this like
little chain thing i did with the warped
planks
and i'm pretty happy with the detailing
that i've done however i think i
probably overused the uh the soul
lanterns they kind of stick out a little
bit but i'm working on it i'm gonna
figure all the rest of it out now i want
to draw your attention over here because
i am actually making proper farms again
it's basically just copying oh come on
more torches it's basically just a
simple replica of your standard melon
and pumpkin farm one of the ones that i
have down there but i'm going to
replicate this one to maybe another one
on top but what i didn't anticipate is
how expensive it would be i mean look at
all these hoppers look at all these
pistons and observers they are not cheap
blocks
at all even the note blocks aren't cheap
either so
i'm midway through doing that but i'm
realizing quite quickly i might have a
bottleneck problem uh when all of these
are in but we'll we'll see how that goes
all of this of course fuels my trading
hall downstairs and it seems that the
melons have already had quite an impact
so this is going what i would call
pretty well now obviously i have an
issue where i've got basically two
separate bases i've got the lovely
looking mansion upstairs and then i have
the more technical storage downstairs
and i don't have a good way to get
between the two and also my portal is
there
so what i really need to figure out is
how i can link the two without having to
fly in and out of these and i was
looking at this the the fireplace
and i was wondering
this should in theory line directly up
yep
with this room here
so you fall straight through there
there's the possibility
that i could create well not not just an
empty hole but maybe an a lift or an
elevator or something could go here
maybe a fireman pole i don't know
something so i have quick access from
room to room man these
where are these extra zombies now
oh
okay well looking for the zombie i found
the culprit of the dinging machine
oh my goodness there's so many
this is the this is now the third one
well i think i know what impulses yeah
there's one in every single one of these
no wonder i'm constantly hearing dinging
everywhere
has he done
the other side as well
oh he went all out
he really went all out
oh man
really everywhere
you would have thought with this many i
would have heard it like non-stop there
we go that
might be the last of them i i think
impulse built about 12 in total
so that's where i'm kind of at with the
interior of
my the two sides of my base i'm gonna
figure out how to link them up in a
really nice way and then over on this
side hopefully this will be like the
super smelter maybe some sheep in here
not entirely sure over this side is
going to be the villager breeder so i
can expand my trading hall
basically this is all stuff i should
have done
at the beginning of the season well i
did you know like i've got a super
smelter over in the hobbit hole and this
is now defunct but i should have
upgraded a long time ago so this has
been a long time coming however i know
what you all really want to know
where am i going to make a secret base
in corrales base so with impulse and
b-dubs involved
we all decided that we didn't want to
know where each other's secret bases are
and we're all going to try and build in
corrales city and there it is
the question of course
is where
where where where
do we make our secret base i think for
me
it's got to be close enough to corrales
central hub that i can keep an eye on
him but i also need it to be
i needed to be central i think that's
the that's the key there's no point
making a secret base over there because
you're just not part of the action
however i have noticed
that there is my mansion for half of my
mansion from season
six
man i i you know this is i did a
tutorial on this build a really long
time ago never did interior mind so this
is pretty cool
but look i mean there's interior
everywhere there's so many opportunities
for secret bases but there's no way i
can tell you guys straight away where it
is i just i just can't trust you i'm
sorry
so i think that is where we're gonna
have to leave today's episode
i'm gonna figure out where i can hide
the secret base
in this enormous city
and then hopefully i can link up with
bdubs impulse and we can begin
the shenanigans and we shall see how
that goes okay so all there is left to
say is thank you very much for watching
i hope you enjoyed the video uh please
do consider subscribing if you haven't
already and by the way
please hear my warning about not
spamming the hermit's comment it's not a
nice thing to have happen so if there's
we only need a few bits of diversionary
tactics so we've got to be super
respectful in in our shenanigans i know
it's all good fun but you know if you
see a funny comment just leave a thumbs
up on it and that's all we need to do
there's a creeper down there
goodbye